[
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "A train company provides an online service for passengers to find train routes. What information should the passenger input?",
    "correct_answer": "Destination",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Number of train stops",
      "Train fare",
      "HKID number"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "A museum is going to digitize some valuable antique books. What is the major benefit of digitizing these books?",
    "correct_answer": "More people can access these books",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The books can be destroyed to save space",
      "It promotes good ergonomic practices",
      "The books can be encrypted to strengthen security"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "A teacher scan and store his written paper notes as digital image so his students can use computers to search and view the notes. Which of the following is NOT a benefit of such digitization?",
    "correct_answer": "The intellectual property of the notes can be well protected",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The students can access the notes easily",
      "The teacher can easily make copies of the notes",
      "The teacher need not to type the notes himself"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "Which of the following is characteristic of the Information Age?",
    "correct_answer": "Information is widely distributed via Internet",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "All company information on the Internet is correct",
      "Reliance on manual labor for production is increased",
      "Information is harder to access by the public"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an impact caused by the emergence of the Information Age?",
    "correct_answer": "More office space is needed",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "More ICT-related jobs appear and change the job market",
      "Students have more opportunities to access information and learn new things",
      "Number of social media users has increased"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "Which of the following processes is an example of data collection?",
    "correct_answer": "Taking Towngas meter readings",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Inserting a credit card into an automated teller machine",
      "Putting a photo on a scanner for scanning",
      "Entering grades of students examination into a spreadsheet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "Which of the following statements about a check digit for a data item is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "The check digit can be used to detect errors",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data item should contain at least 8 characters",
      "The check digit can correct errors",
      "The data item should contain at least one special character"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "A teacher enters the examination marks of students from a mark sheet into a spreadsheet. Then he prints out the marks. What should he do next?",
    "correct_answer": "Check the printout against the marksheet",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Destroy the mark sheet",
      "Sort the students by mark",
      "Find the student with the lowest mark"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "Each book in a library contains a unique identity number. Its check digit is used to detect errors. Which of the following errors CANNOT be found by the check digit?",
    "correct_answer": "Another book's identity number is entered",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A digit is mistakenly typed as another digit in the identity number",
      "Two digits are swapped in the identity number",
      "A digit is mistakenly typed as a letter in the identity number."
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "During data input, which of the following can minimize input errors?",
    "correct_answer": "Double entry",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Two's complement",
      "Captcha",
      "Checkboxes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "A code consisting 8 binary bits adapts parity check. If only one of the following codes is valid, which one is it?",
    "correct_answer": "1011 1010",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1010 1001",
      "1111 1111",
      "1101 0111"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "What is the benefit of using date picker instead of a textbox for entering dates into a web page?",
    "correct_answer": "It is more user-friendly",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Errors can be detected by check digit",
      "It eliminates the need for a calendar view",
      "Users can enter dates in any format they choose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "When creating an online email account, it is asked to enter the password twice. <br> <img src='/static/data/201707.webp'> <br> What is the purpose of re-entering the password?",
    "correct_answer": "Data verification",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Data collection",
      "Data validation",
      "Data compression"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "When changing the password of an online email account, which of the following is an example of data verification?",
    "correct_answer": "Input a new password twice",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Input a new password and an SMS verification code",
      "Input a new password that consists of at least 8 characters",
      "Input the old password and a new password"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "An error is detected in the mark field of a school scoring system. Which of the following CANNOT detect the error?",
    "correct_answer": "Uniqueness check",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Field presence check",
      "Range check",
      "Type check"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "What are the 8-bit one's complement and 4-bit two's complement of the binary number 101?",
    "correct_answer": "11111010 and 1011",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "11111011 and 1011",
      "11111010 and 1010",
      "11111011 and 1010"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Seven segment display consists of 7 separate LEDs. Each LED can be set to either 'ON' or 'OFF'. A pattern can be displayed by turning some or none of the LEDs on. <br> <img src='/static/data/201306.webp'> <br> How many different patterns can it display?",
    "correct_answer": "128",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "7",
      "14",
      "49"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "With two's complement representation, which of the following operations CANNOT produce an overflow error?",
    "correct_answer": "Adding a positive integer and a negative integer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Adding two positive integers",
      "Adding two negative integers",
      "Subtracting a positive integer from a negative integer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Decrement the following numbers using 8-bit two's complement representation by 1. Which one will create an overflow error?",
    "correct_answer": "10000000",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "01111111",
      "10000001",
      "11111111"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "In a computer system, 10 bits are reserved for user identity number, 53 bits are reserved for user's name and the last bit is a parity bit. What is the maximum number of user accounts in the system?",
    "correct_answer": "1024",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "63",
      "10^10",
      "10^53"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Arrange the following 4-bit numbers using two's complement representation in ascending order. <br> (1) 0111 <br> (2) 0110 <br> (3) 1000 <br> (4) 1111",
    "correct_answer": "(3), (4), (2), (1)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "(1), (2), (4), (3)",
      "(2), (1), (3), (4)",
      "(4), (3), (1), (2)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "There are 65544 participants in a game. Each participants has been given a unique identity code stored in an NFS (Near Field Communication) card. What is the minimum storage size required in each card?",
    "correct_answer": "3 bytes",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1 byte",
      "2 bytes",
      "4 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "What is the order of sizes of the three character sets, ASCII, Big-5 code and GB code?",
    "correct_answer": "ASCII < Big-5 code = GB code",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "ASCII < Big-5 code < GB code",
      "ASCII < GB code < Big-5 code",
      "ASCII = Big-5 code = GB code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "In a program, 8 bits and 16 bits are used to store a character and an integer respectively. How many bytes are required to store the string 'DSE2024'?",
    "correct_answer": "7 bytes",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "11 bytes",
      "56 bytes",
      "88 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following number has the largest decimal value?",
    "correct_answer": "11111111 using 8-bit unsigned binary representation",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "11111111 using 8-bit two's complement representation",
      "01111111 using 8-bit two's complement representation",
      "01111111 using 8-bit unsigned binary representation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of using Unicode over Big-5 code?",
    "correct_answer": "Unicode has bigger character set",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Unicode is cross-platform",
      "Unicode is easier to implement in programming languages",
      "Unicode supports traditional Chinese characters"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "The following calculations involve 8-bit numbers using two's complement representation. Which one will generate an overflow error?",
    "correct_answer": "01111111 + 00000001",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "10000001 + 01111111",
      "11111111 + 00000001",
      "01011111 + 00100000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following character encoding methods can be used to represent Japanese text?",
    "correct_answer": "Unicode",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "ASCII",
      "Big-5 code",
      "GB code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following statements about two's complement is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "The minimum value for an N-bit number is -2^(N - 1)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The maximum value for an N-bit number is 2^(N - 1)",
      "The maximum value for an N-bit number is 2^N - 1",
      "The minimum value for an N-bit number is -2^N - 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "There are one hundred 300GB video files. Without any file reorganization and compression, how many 2TB hard disks are needed to store all video files?",
    "correct_answer": "17",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "15",
      "16",
      "32"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following decimal values is equivalent to 10111011 in 8-bit two's complement representation?",
    "correct_answer": "-69",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "69",
      "68",
      "-68"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "Which of the following does NOT involve converting data between digital and analog forms?",
    "correct_answer": "Reading a presentation file",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Playing mp3 music",
      "Recording videos using a camera",
      "Scanning a text file"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "A WAV file, which is a common audio file, consists of a header. Which of the following items is stored in the header?",
    "correct_answer": "Sampling rate",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Compression ratio",
      "Type of instrument used",
      "Type of audio player supported"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "Chris converts the file image.wav to image.mp3. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "He wants to reduce the file size of te file",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "He wants to store the file in blue ray disc",
      "He wants to increase the resolution of the file",
      "He wants to improve the quality of the file"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "Chris plans to upload his photos to cloud storage. What is the benefit of using PNG format instead of JPG format in this case?",
    "correct_answer": "PNG supports transparency",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "PNG uses more pixel to represent images",
      "PNG has more color",
      "PNG has smaller file size"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "What fomatting feature is used in the spreadsheet below? <br> <img src='/static/data/201207.webp'>",
    "correct_answer": "Wrap text",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Merge cells",
      "Shrink text to fit",
      "Row height"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Chris wants to produce a list of students who get 40 marks or below in a test, order by their score in ascending order. What functions should he use?",
    "correct_answer": "Filering and sorting",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Filtering and searching",
      "Sorting and searching",
      "Sorting and Grouping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Chris uses 'what-if' analysis in a spreadsheet to solve a problem. Which of the following statement about the analysis is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "The 'what-if' analysis involves different data sets",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The 'what-if' analysis involves different solutions of the problem",
      "The problem involves a database file",
      "The problem involves a document file"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Chris wants to create a chart to display the number of programmers in different age groups. Which type of chart is most appropriate?",
    "correct_answer": "<img src='/static/data/201407_1.webp'>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<img src='/static/data/201407_2.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/201407_3.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/201407_4.webp'>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Consider the spreadsheet below. <br> <br> <img src='/static/data/201510.webp'> <br> <br> What is the output value of the following formula? <br> <code>=COUNTIF(A2:A7,A3)</code>",
    "correct_answer": "2",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1",
      "3",
      "0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "In a spreadsheet, a 3-digit teacher ID (000, 001, ..., 999) is used in some cells. Which cell format should be used?",
    "correct_answer": "Text format",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "General format",
      "Date format",
      "Number format"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "When editing numberical data in a spreadsheet, which of the following statements is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "Relevant image will be updated automatically",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Relevant formulae will be updated automatically",
      "Relevant charts with the numerical data will be updated automatically",
      "Relevant data in the same spreadsheet will be updated automatically"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "For a company, in which of the following examples should 'what-if' scenarios in spreadsheet be used?",
    "correct_answer": "Estimates monthly expenses by changing different parameters",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Produces monthly sales analysis",
      "Compares slaes data from different branches",
      "Produce different solutions for a problem"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Which of the following chart settings are required to produce a chart in a spreadsheet file?",
    "correct_answer": "Data source and Chart type",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Data source and Axis",
      "Chart type and Legend",
      "Axis and Legend"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "In order to summarize and calculate the sum of expenses of each department in different categories, what spreadsheet feature should be used?",
    "correct_answer": "Pivot table",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Multiple worksheets",
      "'What-if' analysis",
      "Sorting data using multiple criteria"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Which of the following is the best key field for students in a school library database?",
    "correct_answer": "Student ID",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Name",
      "Residential telephone number",
      "Class and class number"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "In a database management system, a form is designed for clerk to enter data. Why does he design a form?",
    "correct_answer": "It is more user-friendly",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Multimedia files can be imported",
      "More data can be entered at the same time",
      "The data entry requires less system computation time"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Which operations are performed by the following SQL command? <br> <code>SELECT AVG(SCORE) FROM EXAM WHERE NAME='CHRIS' GROUP BY SUBJECT</code>",
    "correct_answer": "Filtering and grouping",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Sorting and filtering",
      "Counting and Sorting",
      "Grouping and counting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Why are data of birth instead of ages are stored in most database?",
    "correct_answer": "No data update is required",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Personal privacy can be better protected",
      "Less computational time is required",
      "The related SQL queries are simpler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Only one record is retrieved after executing the following SQL command. Which of the following is a possible reason? <br> <code>SELECT NAME, PHONE FROM EMPLOYEE WHERE NAME='CHRIS'</code>",
    "correct_answer": "Only one record has 'CHRIS' as the content of NAME",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "There is only one record in CHRIS",
      "The content of NAME or PHONE in the remaining records is empty",
      "Other fields in EMPLOYEE are hidden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "'Big data' refers to the huge amount of data collected which is difficult to process using database management system. Which of the following is NOT an example of 'big data'?",
    "correct_answer": "Unfinished homework",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Human DNA",
      "User behaviour in a social networking platform",
      "Images used for training image recognition AI"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "When using a database management systems, what is the major purpose of a query?",
    "correct_answer": "Extract information from a database",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Adjust the layout of a database report",
      "Help user enter data",
      "Collect feedback from users"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "A database table is used to storing records for library checkout service, where students can borrow and return books from a library. Which of the following fields are essential?",
    "correct_answer": "Student ID and time",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Student name and time",
      "Student ID and librarian ID",
      "Student name and librarian ID"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "What is the major benefit of using a form in a database management system?",
    "correct_answer": "Simplifies data entry",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Simplifies report printing",
      "Saves storage space",
      "Filters irrelevant data in the database table"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Chris is producing the student report cards using the data stored in a database. What should he do?",
    "correct_answer": "Create reports using database software",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Insert multimedia elements to the report card using word processing software",
      "Create SQL commands using spreadsheet software",
      "Use the 'what-if' analysis to estimate the average score"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "The table <code>TABLE</code> has four records, as shown below. <br> <img src='/static/data/201514.webp'> <br> What is the output of the following SQL command? <br> <code> SELECT ID FROM TABLE WHERE NAME < 'CHRISTINE' AND SCORE > 70</code>",
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A",
      "C",
      "D"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Study the following three SQL commands. <br> <code>SELECT * FROM STUDENT</code> <br> <code>SELECT * FROM STUDENT WHERE class = '4A'</code> <br> <code>SELECT class FROM STUDENT</code> <br> The results of all three SQL commands are the same. Which of the following is NOT possible?",
    "correct_answer": "There are more than one fields in <code>STUDENT</code>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<code>STUDENT</code> is empty",
      "The value of <code>class</code> is <code>'4A'</code> in all records",
      "<code>class</code> is the only field in <code>STUDENT</code>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Which of the following data types is most suitable for representing phone numbers in a database management system?",
    "correct_answer": "Text",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Integer",
      "Character",
      "Boolean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Chris wants to upgrade the DDR4 64GB 2666MHz RAM of his computer to DDR5 64GB 4200MHz RAM with higher data transfer rate. Which of the following features should be considered most?",
    "correct_answer": "Motherboard design",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "CPU computational power",
      "Hard disk storage capacity",
      "Power consumption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "What is the main function of memory cache in CPU?",
    "correct_answer": "To facilitate the computation in CPU",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "To increase the memory storage capacity",
      "To support multi-core processors on the motherboard",
      "To store the operating system of the computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following components is least involved in video playback?",
    "correct_answer": "ROM",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "CPU",
      "RAM",
      "GPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "In an instruction fetch cycle, which of the following register is not involved?",
    "correct_answer": "Accumulator",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Memory Data Register (MDR)",
      "Memory Address Register (MAR)",
      "Instruction Register (IR)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "A 12-core CPU is generally better than a 8-core CPU because...",
    "correct_answer": "More tasks can be done simultaneously",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Lower power consumption",
      "A GPU is not needed in the motherboard",
      "Higher main memory capacity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following components in a CPU fetches an instruction from the main memory?",
    "correct_answer": "Control Unit (CU)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Memory Address Register (MAR)",
      "Memory Data Register (MDR)",
      "Program Counter (PC)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following statements about memory cache in CPU is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "It has higher data transfer rate than RAM",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is a secondary storage",
      "It stores the date and time",
      "It has higher memory capacity than RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "The clock rate of a CPU is 2.60 GHz. Which of the following statement is true?",
    "correct_answer": "The CPU performs 2.60 x 10^9 clock cycles in a second",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The CPU perform 2.60 x 10^9 instructions in a second",
      "The word length of buses in CPU is 2.60 x 10^9",
      "The memory cache of the CPU transfers 2.60 x 10^9 instructions in a second"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about ROM is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "ROM stores the date and time",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "ROM has smaller storage size than RAM",
      "ROM is non-volatile",
      "ROM has lower data transfer rate than RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Arrange the following steps in a machine cycle. <br> (1) Executes the instruction <br> (2) Writes data in memory <br> (3) Decode the instruction into operation code and operands <br> (4) Retrieves the instruction from the memory",
    "correct_answer": "(4), (3), (1), (2)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "(4), (2), (3), (1)",
      "(3), (4), (1), (2)",
      "(3), (2), (4), (1)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about the registers in CPU is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Their data transfer rate are high",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Their storage capacity are high",
      "They are non-volatile",
      "Some of them are used to store the operating system of the computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about the fetch-decode-execute cycle in CPU is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Machine code is involved in the cycle",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "CMOS is used in the cycle",
      "The order of the instructions in the cycle mainly depends on the CPU clock rate",
      "The cycle is mainly used for device management"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about the accumulator in a CPU is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "It is used by the Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU) for calculation",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is used by the Control Unit (CU) to store a memory address temporarily",
      "It is used by the Control Unit (CU) to store the instruction fetched from the main memory",
      "It is used by the Control Unit (CU) to control the flow of data between registers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about the components in a computer is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "The flag registers are used to store data about the state of the processor",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU) is used to control the flow of data between registers",
      "The data transfer rate of registers is slower than that of the main memory",
      "Data buses are used to transfer control signals between the main board and input/output devices"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following are NOT the benefits of Solid-state Drive (SSD) over hard disk?",
    "correct_answer": "Higher storage capacity",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Higher data transfer rate",
      "Lower power consumption",
      "More shock resistant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Why is Solid-state Drive (SSD) more commonly used in laptop computers instead of hard disk?",
    "correct_answer": "The physical size of a SSD is smaller",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The storage capacity of a SSD is larger",
      "Mobile devices does not support hard disk",
      "The cost of a SSD is smaller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Arrange the following in ascending order by data transfer rate. <br> (1) Solid-state Drive (SSD) <br> (2) Registers <br> (3) Memory cache <br> (4) RAM",
    "correct_answer": "(1), (4), (3), (2)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "(1), (4), (2), (3)",
      "(3), (2), (4), (1)",
      "(2), (3), (4), (1)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following only supports sequential access?",
    "correct_answer": "Magnetic tape",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Blu-ray disk",
      "DVD-RW",
      "Flash memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following will enlarge the images and text displayed on a visual display unit?",
    "correct_answer": "Reduce the screen resolution",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Increase the color depth",
      "Increase the screen resolution",
      "Increase the font size of the text"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Chris upgrades his desktop computer with a touch screen. What is the major benefit of this update?",
    "correct_answer": "A touch screen allows for easier hand eye coordination than a keyboard",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "This is a good ergonomic practice",
      "More utilities application can be used",
      "A touch screen can be installed easily"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Convenient stores use thermal printers instead of dot-matrix printers to print receipts. Which of the following is NOT a reason for using thermal printers?",
    "correct_answer": "More durable receipts",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Less printing noise",
      "Shorter printing time",
      "More portable"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "The following QR code is printed on an leaflet so readers can scan the code and browse the information online using smart phone. What information is encoded in the QR code? <br> <img src='/static/data/201414.webp'>",
    "correct_answer": "URL",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Text information about the leaflet",
      "Email address of the company",
      "Binary codes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following practice for desktop computers is environmental-friendly?",
    "correct_answer": "Enable the power management function",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Lower the screen resolution",
      "Use CRT monitors instead of LED monitors",
      "Adjust the monitor to a suitable angle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following attributes can highly affect the accuracy of the conversion when scanning a document?",
    "correct_answer": "DPI",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "PPI",
      "Color depth",
      "Image size"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "In a convenient store, the original barcode of a product is shown below. <br> <img src='/static/data/201518.webp'> <br> Part of the barcode of the product is modified. Which of the following CANNOT be properly scanned?",
    "correct_answer": "<img src='/static/data/201518_1.webp'>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<img src='/static/data/201518_2.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/201518_3.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/201518_4.webp'>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Chris wants to buy a keyboard for his tablet computer. Which of the following connections is least commonly used for keyboards?",
    "correct_answer": "Fibre optics",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "USB cable",
      "Bluetooth",
      "WiFi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Chris wants to buy a color laser printer for use at home. What specification should he consider?",
    "correct_answer": "Printing speed",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Brightness",
      "Resolution",
      "Color depth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "What is the major difference between barcode and QR code?",
    "correct_answer": "QR code can represent more data",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The area of QR code must be larger than that of barcode",
      "Only QR code can be read by a smartphone",
      "QR code cannot represents text"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "What is the benefit of using a fingerprint over a smartcard authentication in computer systems?",
    "correct_answer": "The security is higher",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The system development cost is cheaper",
      "Users' privacy can be protected",
      "It is more hygiene"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following about QR code is NOT correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Only one type of data, such as integer or boolean, can be encoded at a time",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Information on the QR code may be decoded even if part of the QR code is damaged",
      "The QR code can be scanned successfully horizontally or vertically",
      "The security of QR code is generally low"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Chris tries to download an entertainment software on his computer but fails. Which of the following is a possible reason?",
    "correct_answer": "The software does not support the operating system of his computer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "His CPU clock rate is too low for the software",
      "He does not have a virtual keyboard",
      "He does not have a driver for his GPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following applications in a computer can prevent the infection of a virus?",
    "correct_answer": "Firewall",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Email client program",
      "Utilities application",
      "Driver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "The following diagram shows a basic computer system. <br> <img src='/static/data/201320.webp'> <br> Which of the following does <b>K</b> not responsible for?",
    "correct_answer": "Increases the number of application programs",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Controls devices through devices drivers",
      "Memory management",
      "Schedules the running of processes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "The 64-bit version of an operating system is better than 32-bit version because",
    "correct_answer": "The operating system can address more memory locations",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The processing power of the CPU is higher",
      "The data transfer rate of RAM is higher",
      "The bus width is higher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Chris does not download patches to upgrade the operating system of his computer. Which of the following best describes the possible consequences?",
    "correct_answer": "The operating system may be less secure against hackers",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The computer cannot connect to the Internet",
      "The IP address of the computer may need to be changed",
      "The license of the operating system will soon expire and he will have to re-install it"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Chris connects a new USE flash drive to his computer, but he does not need to install a driver program for the USB flash drive. Why not?",
    "correct_answer": "The operating system in the cmoputer has the driver program for the flash drive already",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A USB flash drive does not require a driver program",
      "The flash drive uses the same driver program as the printer",
      "The driver is downloaded automatically to the computer when connecting the USB flash drive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following functions does an operating system usually have?",
    "correct_answer": "Provision of a user interface",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Construction of web pages",
      "Analysis of AI chatbot",
      "Management of email"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of using a compressed file?",
    "correct_answer": "The content can be previewed before downloading the compressed file",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The folder structure can be maintained",
      "The compressed file can be protected by password",
      "The compressed file has smaller file size"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following items is NOT system software?",
    "correct_answer": "Word processor",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Operating system",
      "Driver program",
      "Disk defragmenter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "What information is usually NOT provided by the system monitoring software in an opreating system?",
    "correct_answer": "Private key",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Current processes",
      "Memory usage",
      "Network traffic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "The file sizes of the following original files are all 1MB. Under normal circumstances, after compressing them, which compressed file has the largest file size?",
    "correct_answer": "D.mp3 -> D.zip",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A.html -> A.zip",
      "B.doc -> B.zip",
      "C.txt -> C.zip"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is a major difference between system softwares (SS) and application softwares (AS)?",
    "correct_answer": "(SS) interacts with application softwares but (AS) interacts with users",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "(SS) are usually written in high level languages but (AS) are usually written in low level languages",
      "(SS) are used to perform specific tasks but (AS) are used for operating computer hardware",
      "(SS) run on the platform provided by (AS) but (AS) maintain system resources for (SS)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following can help reduce the time needed to access files in a hard disk?",
    "correct_answer": "Defragmentation software",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "RAID",
      "NAS",
      "Driver program"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "What is the benefit of defragmentation?",
    "correct_answer": "Improves data transfer rate of hard disk",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Creates more free spaces in hard disk",
      "Reduces the disk space occupied by files",
      "Uncompresses file in hard disk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a major networking functions of a typical computer system?",
    "correct_answer": "Control the network bandwidth of a connection between two computers",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Allow communication between computers",
      "Protect the computers from unauthorized access",
      "Monitor network traffics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following about driver program is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Enables the operating system to control a printer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Enables the operating system to manage computer resources",
      "Monitors the incoming network traffic",
      "Monitors the usage of CPU and RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of using mobile device to read books?",
    "correct_answer": "The ergonomic design of mobile devices helps relieve eye strain",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Mobile devices provide various functions which make reading convernient",
      "It is convenient for carrying a lot of books",
      "It is easy to search for different books through internet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the mode of operation of a global positioning system (GPS) in a car?",
    "correct_answer": "Real-time processing",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Batch processing",
      "Distributed processing",
      "Parallel processing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is advantage of using table computers in e-learning?",
    "correct_answer": "Table computers are highly porable and student can access to Internet easily",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Tablet computers can store a large amount of learning materials so that online resources are not needed",
      "Tablet computers have a high processing power",
      "Tablet computers support the use of ergonomic mouse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "A company has a single physical server that can run multiple operating systems and applications in a virtual environment. Which of the following best describes such system?",
    "correct_answer": "Virtualization",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Batch processing system",
      "Distributed processing system",
      "Parallel system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "A report generation system generates report of a database at the end of each week, summarizing the data during that week. Which of the following best describes such system?",
    "correct_answer": "Batch processing",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Real time processing",
      "Parallel processing",
      "Distributed processing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following systems depends on network connectivity?",
    "correct_answer": "Real-time system",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Single-user system",
      "Batch processing system",
      "Distributed processing system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following is a possible consequence of lowering the clock rate of a CPU in a desktop computer?",
    "correct_answer": "Consumes less electricity",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Increases the accuracy of computation",
      "Enhances the performance of the WiFi connection",
      "Increases the protection of the computing against hacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following CPU has the best computational power?",
    "correct_answer": "Quad-code, 2.8GHz",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Quad-code, 2.6GHz",
      "Dual-core, 2.8GHz",
      "Dual-code, 2.6GHz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following computers takes the shortest time to boot up? A computer with...",
    "correct_answer": "4 GB RAM and 512 GB SSD",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "2 GB RAM and 512 GB SSD",
      "4 GB RAM and 2 TB Hard disk",
      "2 GB RAM and 2 TB Hard disk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "When buying a wireless broadband router for a network at home, which of the following considerations is not necessary?",
    "correct_answer": "The IP address of the router",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data transfer rate of the broadband connection",
      "Security protocols",
      "Coverage of the router"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Why is network interface cards (NIC) used in a computer network?",
    "correct_answer": "NICs connect computers to the network",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The network needs to support data transfer of at least 10 GB per second",
      "NICs convert analog signals into digital signals and vice versa",
      "NICs provide a user interface for monitoring the network traffics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "In the following diagram, X is a network connecting device that allows customers to order through cashiers using dedicated terminals. <br> <img src='/static/data/201328.webp'> <br> What is the function of X?",
    "correct_answer": "To connect devices and help device communicate with another device",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "To boost the signal transmitted between devices",
      "To connect devices to the Internet",
      "To monitor and filter incoming and outgoing network traffic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following about switch is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "It joins two network",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It connects computers to form a LAN",
      "It controls the network traffic in a network",
      "It learns which devices to transmit information to"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following can be greatly improved if more cache memory is installed in a NAS?",
    "correct_answer": "Data throughput",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Computation power",
      "Storage capacity",
      "Network bandwidth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris has a wireless network with Internet access at home. He finds that the file transfer rate between two computers through the network is very low. What is the possible reason for this?",
    "correct_answer": "There is a thick wall between the computers and the wireless router",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "No wireless router is installed",
      "The Internet connection is disconnected",
      "The communication protocols used by the two computers are different"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Arrange the following communication links in ascending order of data transfer rates. <br> (1) Cat 6 (twisted pair) <br> (2) Satellite <br> (3) Fibre optics",
    "correct_answer": "(2), (1), (3)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "(2), (3), (1)",
      "(3), (2), (1)",
      "(1), (2), (3)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following is advantage of setting up a wireless network to replace a wired network?",
    "correct_answer": "Increase mobility of computers",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Increase network speed",
      "Enhance network security",
      "Increase network coverage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "A router should be used to connect...",
    "correct_answer": "Two different networks",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A printer and a computer",
      "Two computers",
      "A computer to a server"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Below is the computer network for Chris's home: <br> <img src='/static/data/201921.webp'> <br> What are X and Y?",
    "correct_answer": "X: Switch, Y: Access point",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "X: Access point, Y: Network interface card",
      "X: Firewall, Y: Switch",
      "X: Modem, Y: Access point"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of using a LAN over a WAN?",
    "correct_answer": "Higher data transfer rate",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Larger network coverage",
      "Lower setup cost",
      "Higher security"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "<src img='/static/data/202020.webp'> <br> In order to allow all desktop computers to connect to the wireless printer, which of the following actions should be taken?",
    "correct_answer": "The wireless printer should be connected to the AP",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The AP should be installed between the switch and teacher's computer",
      "The teacher's computer should be turned on",
      "The switch should be replaced by a router"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris cannot access to a website by entering <code>https://web.wahyan.edu.hk<code>, but he can do so by entering <code>http://118.142.16.87</code>. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "The DNS server is out of service",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The web server is out of service",
      "Her browser needs to be updated to the newest version",
      "The router used at home is out of order"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris can view an online video on the computer at home but not on the computer in his school. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "The browser does not support the video playback",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The operating system does not support the video playback",
      "The video is not in MP4 format",
      "The maximum data transfer rate of the school network is low"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "When browsing a web page, which of the following will NOT be involved?",
    "correct_answer": "PKI",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "IP",
      "URL",
      "HTTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "What is the benefit of downloading files through HTTPS over using Peer-to-Peer (P2P) file sharing software?",
    "correct_answer": "HTTPS is a secure channel",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data transfer rate is higher",
      "It is illegal to use P2P file sharing software",
      "TCP/IP protocol can be used"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "A smart air conditioner allows the customer to adjust the cooling functions of the air conditioner from a smart phone. What is the advantage of this?",
    "correct_answer": "It is convenient for controlling the air conditioner",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is more secure than a normal air conditioner",
      "The air conditioner has higher cooling power",
      "It uses less electricity than a normal air conditioner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris is making a web site so everyone can access his web site through any one of the following links: <br> <code> web.chris.com </code> <br> <code> en.chris.com </code> <br> <code> www.chris.com.hk </code> <br> <code> intranet.chris.com </code> <br> <code> web.chris.com.hk </code> <br> How many domain names does he need to register?",
    "correct_answer": "2",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1",
      "4",
      "5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "An IPv6 address consists of 8 groups of 4-digit hexadecimal numbers separated by colons. How many possible IPv6 addresses are there?",
    "correct_answer": "32^16",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "32^2",
      "16^32",
      "32^10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following can be used to identify a host computer on the Internet?",
    "correct_answer": "IP address",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "MAC address",
      "Computer name",
      "Private key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Chris takes some photos using a digital camera and he wants to upload them to his website. Which of the following image file types are suitable for him to use?",
    "correct_answer": "PNG and JPG",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "PNG and TIFF",
      "GIF and JPG",
      "GIF and TIFF"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Chris lives in Hong Kong but he likes to buy things throught online shopping websites of shops around the world. Which of the following is a possible reason he choose to buy online?",
    "correct_answer": "He can buy things that are not for sale in Hong Kong",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "He can select and buy things during the office hours in other places",
      "His privacy can be protected",
      "He can use credit card to pay"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following features do online shopping websites usually have?",
    "correct_answer": "A database management system (DBMS)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Mainframe computers",
      "A peer-to-peer (P2P) network",
      "Object recognition system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following is a benefit of including operators like '-' in search strings when using Internet search engines?",
    "correct_answer": "The search results can be more relevant",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The search time can be shorter",
      "The search results include the title of web pages only",
      "The search results can include both local and foreign web sites"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following discloses information about the location of the computer?",
    "correct_answer": "Internet Service Provider",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Network interface card",
      "Operating system",
      "Private key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "In a company, all URLs browsed through the office computers are recorded by a proxy server. Which of the following is true?",
    "correct_answer": "The records should be checked by authorized staffs only",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The URLs should be recorded during office hours only",
      "The records are the digital property of the staff",
      "The company has committed a computer crime"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "A cloud computing company not only provides cloud storage but also allows customers to make their files available offline. What is the major benefit of this arragement?",
    "correct_answer": "Customers can edit the files without Internet connection",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Customers can remove the files form the cloud storage to save space",
      "Customers can access the file through their smart phones",
      "Customers can use more different features to modify their files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following matches of components of information system and its example is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Networks: WAN",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Personnel: TCP",
      "Data: PKI",
      "Software: NAS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "The Internet of Things (IoT) refers to the networks formed by devices which can collect and exchange data. The networks also usually connected to the Internet. Which of the following items should the devices usually have?",
    "correct_answer": "IP address",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "CPU with high processing power",
      "DNS",
      "Large storage capacity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Chris watches a video using streaming technology and finds that the video does not play smoothly. Which of the following is NOT a possible reason?",
    "correct_answer": "Duration of the video",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Resolution of the video",
      "Method of Internet access",
      "Bandwidth of the Internet connection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following is a government e-service provided by GovHK?",
    "correct_answer": "Enrolling for community recreation and sports programmes",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Applying for admission to universities in Hong Kong",
      "Renewing borrowed school library books",
      "Watching Summer Olympic Games live stream"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "At home, Chris logs on to a computer in his office and does some word processing. Which of the following about the remote logon is true?",
    "correct_answer": "The remote logon supports data encryption",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Both computer should have the same word processing software",
      "Both computer shoudl have the same IP address",
      "Two computers are involved so word processing is faster"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "When watching videos from a website using streaming technology under a wired network, which of the following is NOT involved?",
    "correct_answer": "WPA",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "DNS",
      "IP",
      "HTTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following activities transfers minimal data through the Internet?",
    "correct_answer": "Uploading a web page of 10 KB containing a hyperlink to a 2 GB file",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Sending an email of 10 KB with a 2 MB audio file to 100 receivers",
      "Uploading and converting an image of 10 MB to JPG format using an online tool",
      "Watching a 60-minute video of 500 MB online using streaming technology"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following about streaming technology is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "HTTP cannot be used",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A music performance can be viewed live",
      "Illegal distribution of movies can be controlled",
      "Connecting to the Internet is necessary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "What service will a computer commonly provided for other computers in a LAN?",
    "correct_answer": "File sharing",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Email",
      "Web browsing",
      "Video conferencing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following can improve the quality of video conferencing?",
    "correct_answer": "A higher network bandwifth",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A larger storage capacity",
      "A camera with lower resolution",
      "An adjustable monitor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Chris creates a web page to show a photo, but the photo cannot be displayed in a web browser, as shown below. <br> <img src='/static/data/201325.webp'> <br> What is the possible mistake he has made?",
    "correct_answer": "Used an incorrect filename for the photo",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Adapoted improper text format",
      "Missed some HTML tags",
      "Used GIF instead of JPG format"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "A company develops an internal email system. It adopts HTML format instead of plain text for the email because...",
    "correct_answer": "Text formatting can be applied",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The email size is smaller",
      "Browsers can open the email",
      "The HTTP protocol can be used"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "In HTML, which of the following is an attributes of a table?",
    "correct_answer": "Space between cells",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Domain name of each cells",
      "Media types of the content of cells",
      "Formulae in each cells"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of using HTML format instead of plain text format?",
    "correct_answer": "Text format cannot be opened with a browser",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "HTML file can store hyperlinks",
      "Videos can be displayed when opening HTML file",
      "Background color in HTML file can be changed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Chris edits the font color of a web page. How many different colors can he choose?",
    "correct_answer": "256 * 256 * 256",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "16 * 16 * 16",
      "8 * 8 * 8",
      "3 * 3 * 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Color codes are used when defining the background color in a web page. What is the range of hexadecimal values for the color codes?",
    "correct_answer": "0 to FF",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "0 to 99",
      "1 to 64",
      "1 to AA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "A web page displays some images. Besides the names of the image files, what other information will be included in the HTML code of the web page?",
    "correct_answer": "The size of the image files",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The paths of the image files",
      "The IP address of the server that stores the HTML file",
      "The name of the image owner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Chris wants to upload some photos to his website. Before uploading the photo, what should he do?",
    "correct_answer": "He should reduce the photo size to fit the display",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "If the file size of the photo is too large, he should divide it into smaller files for uploading",
      "He should adjust the resolution of the photo so that it is as high as possible",
      "He should adjust the number of colours shown in the photo to as high as possible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "An IT project manager wants to make a web pages for his company. What should he do first?",
    "correct_answer": "Define the scope of the service",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Evaluate the IT equipment needed",
      "Estimate the project completion data",
      "Set up a project team and recruit programmers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "On a school web page, students can select their class using a drop-down list instead of a text box. What is the major benefit of this design?",
    "correct_answer": "Reduce input errors",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Allow more input words",
      "Reduce computational time",
      "Protect students' privacy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Chris wants to upload some audio to his website, but the website has limited storage space. Which of the following file format is more appropriate?",
    "correct_answer": "MP3",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "WAV",
      "AVI",
      "MPEG2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "A web page of a school displays all of its 16 subjects, as shown below. <br> <img src='/static/data/201727.webp'> <br> Which of the following modifications can let users to clearly view all the subjects without using the scroll bar on the right hand side?",
    "correct_answer": "Uses a table with multiple columns",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Decreases the character spacing",
      "Change the text alignment",
      "Increase the font size of the text"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "The following diagram is part of the folder structure of www.wyhk.edu.hk: <br> <img src='/static/data/201825.webp'> <br> Which of the following URLs is NOT valid?",
    "correct_answer": "<code>http://www.wyhk.edu.hk/data/test.doc</code>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<code>http://www.wyhk.edu.hk/index.html</code>",
      "<code>http://www.wyhk.edu.hk/ict/ict.html</code>",
      "<code>http://www.wyhk.edu.hk/csd/info.txt</code>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Alice sends a group message about burning down her school through a social networking site. Bob receives and forwards this message to invite his friends, but he didn't join the event. Chris receives and read this message from Bob, but he doesn't take any action. Who has/have misused the social networking site and caused damage to the society?",
    "correct_answer": "Alice and Bob only",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Alice only",
      "Alice and Chris only",
      "Alice, Bob and Chris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "At home, Chris unintentionally detects his neighbor's WiFi network without any security measures. He can fully control the wireless router. What should he do?",
    "correct_answer": "Ignore the network connection",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Connect to the network for web browsing only",
      "Connect to the network for transferring small files only",
      "Configure the wireless router with an authentication key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Some teenagers in Hong Kong are addicted to playing online games. Which of the following behaviours is/are common in this group of teenagers?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "They prefer playing online games to joining face-to-face social activities",
      "They play online games as a way of escaping from daily life problems",
      "They feel irritable when being stopped from using computers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "When Chris tries to change the password of his computer account, the following screen is shown. <br> <img src='/static/data/201336.webp'> <br> What is the use of 'Old password'?",
    "correct_answer": "It prevents other people from changing the password",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It improves the password strength",
      "It minimizes typing errors",
      "It allows Chris to login with his old password if he forgets his new password"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following can reduce the threats from using social networking web sites?",
    "correct_answer": "Block or ignore people that you don't know or trust",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Use default privacy settings to restrict access",
      "Only disclose the name and address in the account",
      "Only post photos that have your face in it"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason to not download commercial application program using peer-to-peer file sharing software?",
    "correct_answer": "His action will create digital divide",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The application program may be spyware",
      "He may infringe copyright law",
      "The application program may not receive official updates or support"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a good practice when using online backing system?",
    "correct_answer": "Avoid using wired network when wireless network is available",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Create an uncommon login name",
      "Include special characters for the password",
      "Change the password regularly"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Chris is a teenager and he made a new friend on a social networking web site. The friend wants to meet Chris face-to-face, but his brother suggests him not to meet the friend. What is the major reason?",
    "correct_answer": "The friend's identity is not confirmed",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Chris can make other new friends in the social networking web site",
      "Chris's brother cannot come with him",
      "Chris can meet his other friends"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "In an office network, a technician installs a firewall instead of antivirus software. What is the major reason for this?",
    "correct_answer": "The network can be protected from online security threads",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The computers in the office can be protected from ransomware",
      "File transfer through the network can be faster",
      "The network can withstand attacks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Chris receives an anonymous email, saying tat the attached file hw.exe contains his homework. Chris tries to execute the file but no file is displayed. What is the possible reason?",
    "correct_answer": "The file contains malicious code that harms Chris's computer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Word processing software has not been installed in Chris's computer",
      "The email server cannot execute the file",
      "The email address of the sender is not on Chris's whitelist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "The login page of online banking system usually requires customers to enter a 6-digit number generated by their security token. What is the purpose of using the token?",
    "correct_answer": "Authenticate customers' identity",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Prevent the computer from virus infection",
      "Allow customers to enter a token value without their password",
      "Act as a firewall"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following about phishing email is true?",
    "correct_answer": "Phishing email is typically carries out by sending target recipients an email with a fake web site to acquire their personal information",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Phishing email is a type of advertisement that a company sends out to target recipients",
      "Target recipients will not be able to use their computers for a few days after a phishing attack",
      "To prevent phishing email, recipients should put the email address of the sender of phishing email to their whitelist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Chris receives an anonymous email about instructions on how to download an application and create a new account. The email contains a hyperlink leading to a malicious website and an executable file. Which of the following security issue is NOT involved in the instance?",
    "correct_answer": "DoS attack",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Intrusion",
      "Phishing",
      "Malware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following actions can help identifying whether a web site is safe?",
    "correct_answer": "Verify the digital certificates of the web site",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Ensure that the domain name does not contain '.ru'",
      "Follow hyperlinks in emails sent by trusted adults instead of anonymously",
      "Enable a firewall before browsing the Internet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is security measure an online bank can use to authenticate customers' identities?",
    "correct_answer": "Security token",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Antivirus software",
      "Phone number",
      "Digital watermark"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following has the highest security risks?",
    "correct_answer": "Using a public computer in a cafe to log on to an online bank",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Using mobile phone data to check email",
      "Using a public computer to check the digital certificate of a website",
      "Uploading a document on a personal web site"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Ransomware is malware that encrypts victims' computer files and demands a ransom payment to restore them. How can we minimize the impact of ransomware?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Create backups of computer files regularly",
      "Do not open anonymous or phishing email",
      "Do not download pirated copies of computer software through P2P software"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Why do we need Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) on the Internet?",
    "correct_answer": "Data can be safely transmitted",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The socket of power supply can be protected",
      "Data transmission can be faster",
      "Power usage of data transmission can be reduced"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "What is the major benefit of using data encryption for transferring confidential information over the Internet?",
    "correct_answer": "Hacker cannot read the confidential information easily",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Hacker cannot collect the encrypted data easily",
      "Hacker cannot delete the confidential information easily",
      "Hacker cannot redistribute the encrypted data easily"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Chris finds that his computer is infected by ransomware. Some important document files have been encrypted and cannot be opened. What should he do?",
    "correct_answer": "Report the incident to the police",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Try to put the encrypted files in another computer and open them",
      "Pay the ransom to acquire the password",
      "Restart his computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "In a computer network, which of the following CANNOT protect a user's privacy from a hacker attack?",
    "correct_answer": "Create backup of data",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Update the operating system",
      "Install a firewall",
      "Encrypt important files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Technological Innovations",
    "question": "Which of the following can support an artificial intelligence (AI) system?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Cloud computing",
      "Big data and machine learning",
      "Quantum computing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Technological Innovations",
    "question": "An animation appears on the screen of a smart phone when its camera turned on to view a product in a supermarket. Which of the following is needed to produce the animation?",
    "correct_answer": "Augmented reality (AR)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Data science",
      "3D printing",
      "Projection mapping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "The Hong Kong Government launched the Internet Support Learning Programme in 2011. The Programme helps needy students to acquire computer equipment and Internet access services. What issue is the Government addressing?",
    "correct_answer": "Digital divide",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "e-learning",
      "e-Government",
      "Web 2.0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following does NOT relate to ergonomic matters in office?",
    "correct_answer": "The computer setup contains a mouse",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The viewing angle of the monitor is adjustable",
      "The height of the keyboard tray is adjustable",
      "The office chair contains armrests"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Computer users should take a rest after every hour of computer use. A software company wants to improve its word processing software to include ergonomic feature. What should the software do when a user uses the software for an hour?",
    "correct_answer": "Display an alert message on the screen",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Send an alert email to the user",
      "Shut down the computer automatically",
      "Save the files in the software automatically"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following public policies CANNOT improve the digital divide in Hong Kong?",
    "correct_answer": "Install self-service kiosks in public libraries",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Subsidies low-income families so that they can get Internet access at home",
      "Provide computer equipment to students in need",
      "Given free training courses to citizens who lack basic IT skills"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following can help visually impaired persons to browse the web?",
    "correct_answer": "Braille display device",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Web filtering software",
      "Virtual Private Network (VPN)",
      "Virtual Reality (VR)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Chris wants to buy a tablet computer for his daughter. Which of the following actions is the most appropriate?",
    "correct_answer": "Chris should buy a tablet computer with a longer battery life",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "His daughter should use the tablet computer with a mouse",
      "His daughter should take a 30-minute break after using the tablet computer for 5 minutes",
      "Chris should let his daughter play for 8 hours per day"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Some countries have attracted more females to study ICT courses and to work in the ICT industry. What is the benefit of this policy?",
    "correct_answer": "Improve sex discrimination",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Widen the digital divide",
      "Reduce the computer crime rate",
      "Expand ICT innovations"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason for applying ergonomic design principles to computers in the work environment?",
    "correct_answer": "Saves on cost of setting up computers",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Prevents reptitive strain injury",
      "Provides a customized, adjustable setup for meeting different people's needs",
      "Boost productivity by reducing fatigue and discomfort"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "What can we do for disabled people to improve the access to ICT significantly?",
    "correct_answer": "Develop appropriate tools for disabled people to access ICT",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Give disabled people notebook computers",
      "Set up free computer centres for disabled people to access the Internet",
      "Provide free ICT training for disabled people"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT related to good ergonomic practices in software design?",
    "correct_answer": "Lossy compression images",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Adjustable font size",
      "Appropriate system messages to user",
      "Consistent user interface"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following is the benefit of e-government?",
    "correct_answer": "Government information can be more easily accessed by the public in digital format",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data security of the government information is enhanced",
      "The digital divide in society can be closed",
      "More people can learn about ICT"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT appropriate for enhancing students' information literacy?",
    "correct_answer": "Searching for the installation passward of a software package through an online discussion forum",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Watching documentaries about the ocean online",
      "Reading school newsletters through the school intranet",
      "Finding the history of computers through the Internet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "A student is addicted to online gaming and plays more than 8 hours every day. Which of the following health problems might he encouter?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Sleep problems",
      "Vision problems",
      "Emotion problems"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Which of the following about open source software is true?",
    "correct_answer": "It can be modified and redistributed freely",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is free of program bugs",
      "It is cross-platform",
      "It runs faster in a networked operating system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Which of the following about copyright protection in Hong KOng is true?",
    "correct_answer": "Ideas are not protected unless they are in the form of expressions or products",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Computer programs are not protected unless the copyright owner file a copyright registration application",
      "A book cannot be protected unless the author of the book is deceased",
      "The Customs and Excise Department cannot take legal action against copyright piracy unless the copyright owner file a complaint"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Chris finds a research paper from the Internet so he can finish his passage assignment. Which of the following actions is appropriate?",
    "correct_answer": "Browse other web sites to validate the information",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Put the entire paper in a search engine and search for similar results",
      "Copy some paragraphs of the paper to the assignment",
      "Submit a summary of the paper generated by AI software for his assignment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Chris downloads three different programs A, B and C from the Internet. He can use A for a trial period, changes the source code of B and use only some features in C. Which of the programs is/are shareware?",
    "correct_answer": "A and C only",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "A only",
      "B and C only",
      "B only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Which of the following may infringe intellectual property rights?",
    "correct_answer": "Posting a scanned newspaper on a personal web site",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Sending an email with virus to a friend",
      "Hacking into an online banking account",
      "Uploading your photo to social media platform"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Free online encyclopedias such as Wikipedia contain a huge number of articles. Which of the following about online encyclopedias is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "The articles have no copyright",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "People can search the relevant articles for a topic quickly",
      "These encyclopedias are updated frequently",
      "Information in these encyclopedias may not be completely true"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Davis upload a lot of teaching materials made by Chris to his personal website without Chris's approval. What legal consequences are there of doing this?",
    "correct_answer": "David commits a criminal offence",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Davis needs to modify those teaching materials",
      "Davis needs to change the domain name of his personal website",
      "Chris needs to compensate Davis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "What is the appropriate measure to take to protect the intellectual property rights of photos posted on the Internet?",
    "correct_answer": "Digital watermark",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Digital signature",
      "Security token",
      "Firewall"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Why do people develop open source software?",
    "correct_answer": "They want more people to use their software",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "They want to earn more money from selling their software",
      "They want to own the copyright",
      "They want to produce a bug-free software"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Which of the following will mostlikely infringe copyright in Hong Kong?",
    "correct_answer": "Uploading TV programmes to a personal web site and sharing them with friends",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Using peer-to-peer file sharing software to share personal videos",
      "Broadcasting a street view live through a social media web site",
      "Using peer-to-peer file sharing software to search for an audio file"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "The ASCII codes for the characters 'a' in hexadecimal is 61. What is that of 'z'?",
    "correct_answer": "7A",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "86",
      "60",
      "7B"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "When creating a database table in database software, what should users usually set?",
    "correct_answer": "Primary key",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data of each field",
      "The maximum number of records",
      "The report of the database"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "Chris uses a spreadsheet to store records of books borrowed by students, as follows: <br> <img src='/static/data/202113.webp'> <br> He wants to create a pivot table to find the number of books borrowed by each student. <br> <img src='/static/data/202113_1.webp'> <br> In which of the following areas should 'Student ID' be put?",
    "correct_answer": "ROWS ans VALUES",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "FILTERS",
      "COLUMNS and VALUES",
      "ROWS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following can be the specification of a scanner for scanning documents and images?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "802.11n supported",
      "24-bit color depth",
      "Built-in 64 MB RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following requires a driver program?",
    "correct_answer": "Connecting to a new printer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Editing a word processing document",
      "Removing a software package",
      "Browsing a school website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Chris has a desktop computer installed with 500 GB SSD and a 2 TB hard disk. Why is an operating system installed in the SSD instead of the hard disk?",
    "correct_answer": "The files of the operating system are frequently used",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The storage size required for the operating system is larger than 500 GB",
      "Data files need to be stored in the hard disk",
      "Hard disk is volatile memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following is a recent development in CPU?",
    "correct_answer": "Increasing the clock rate",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Pre-installation of an operating system",
      "Decreasing the number of processing units",
      "Increase the power consumption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer hardware",
    "question": "Chris wants to buy a computer for video editing. Which of the following is the least important factor?",
    "correct_answer": "Storage size of ROM",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Storage size of SSD",
      "Storage size of RAM",
      "CPU clock rate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of using e-book reading device instead of tablet computer to read e-books?",
    "correct_answer": "Higher computational power",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Lower power consumption",
      "Lighter in weight",
      "Lower cost"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer hardware",
    "question": "An instruction of the assembly language is executed in a CPU. Which of the following components decodes the instruction?",
    "correct_answer": "CU",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Buses",
      "Registers",
      "ALU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a multimedia file format?",
    "correct_answer": "ZIP",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "TIFF",
      "AI",
      "MPEG2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Elementary Web Authoring",
    "question": "Which of the following should be considered when designing the user interface of an online shopping platform?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Font size",
      "Color",
      "Language"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris can use his mobile phone in his office to control the appliances connecting to a WiFi network at home. Which of the following is NOT involved?",
    "correct_answer": "Firewall",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "LAN",
      "Router",
      "Access Point"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Chris rents online file storage services for the staff working in his company, instead of setting up file servers. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "Additional technical staff is not needed in the company",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The bandwidth of the Internet connection for the office is not sufficient",
      "Reliance on third-party providers is reduced",
      "Higher ability to tailor hardware and software for the company"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following about HTTP is true?",
    "correct_answer": "It is used to transfer hypertext documents",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is used to translate URLs into IP address",
      "It is used to store the browsing history",
      "It is used to define the content and structure of web content"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "In a school, although a wired network has been installed, the school installs an Access Point connecting to the network. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "Students can use tablet computers for lessons",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The network can be used 24 hours a day",
      "The data transfer rate for the network connections is higher",
      "The security of using Access Point for the network connections is higher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "What should be considered when using information from the Internet to write a report?",
    "correct_answer": "Some information on the Internet is unreliable",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Most information on the Internet is free",
      "Many hackers steal personal information through social media",
      "Font size of text in a user friendly-website should be adjustable"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "A computer receives three data sequences, which are 0101 0111, 1101 0101 and 1110 1011 respectively. Each sequence includes a parity bit. Two of the sequences are found to be corrupted during the transmission. Which of the following describes the situation?",
    "correct_answer": "First and second are corrupted; Even parity check is used",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "First and second are corrupted; Odd parity check is used",
      "Second and third are corrupted; Even parity check is used",
      "Second and third are corrupted; Odd parity check is used"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "A database table <code>RECORD</code> stores fruit name <code>FRUIT</code> and its corresponding amount <code>AMOUNT</code>. Which of the following best describes the result of the query below? <br> <code> SELECT FRUIT FROM RECORD WHERE AMOUNT > 0 ORDER BY AMOUNT <code>",
    "correct_answer": "Fruits are listed in ascending order of amount",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Fruits are listed in descending order of amount",
      "Fruits are listed in ascending order of fruit name",
      "Fruits with low amount are listed in ascending order of amount"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "Which of the following matches of information process and its example is correct?",
    "correct_answer": "Data preparation: validate questionnaires before input",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Data collection: create a statisical chart",
      "Data processing: sort questionnaires for data entry",
      "Data organization: design an online questionnaire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "For a photo, the file size of its BMP image is larger than that of its PNG image because...",
    "correct_answer": "The BMP image is uncompressed",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "BMP represents a bitmap image",
      "PNG supports transparency",
      "The BMP image cannot be shown in a browser"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "In the following spreadsheet, a formula is entered in <code>B6</code> based on <code>B2:B4</code> to calculate the class fee. Classmates want to limit the class fee to $1,000 by cutting the budget for the study tour. <br> <img src='/static/data/202210.webp'> <br> When using the 'goal seek' function for 'what-if' analysis, which of the following sets of data should be used?",
    "correct_answer": "<img src='/static/data/202210_1.webp'>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<img src='/static/data/202210_2.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/202210_3.webp'>",
      "<img src='/static/data/202210_4.webp'>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Why should characters be represented by character sets like ASCII in computers?",
    "correct_answer": "To standardise the data representation",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "To enhance the data encryption",
      "Data in computers is stored in binary number",
      "To reduce computation time of text in softwares"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "Why is information literacy important in a knowledge-based society?",
    "correct_answer": "People should be able to identify fake information and hoaxes on the Internet",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "People should be able to write artificial intelligence (AI) program",
      "People should directly copy information from the Internet for personal use",
      "People should help widen the digital divide in the society"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Introduction to Information Processing",
    "question": "When developing a system, which of the following should be the first item to be considered?",
    "correct_answer": "The purpose of the system",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The technologies involved",
      "The personnel involved",
      "The cost of the system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "A computer runs slow when working on database software. Which of the following hardware components should be upgraded?",
    "correct_answer": "RAM",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "ROM",
      "Network interface card",
      "GPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Chris finds that his computer cannot access to the Internet. Which of the following is a possible cause?",
    "correct_answer": "The network interface card is out of order",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The size of RAM is too small",
      "The data transfer rate of the hard disk is too low",
      "The graphics card is out of order"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Why do we need to update software regularly?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Fix program bug",
      "Provide new functions",
      "Improve the software performance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "In a typical situation, what are P, Q and R? <br> <img src='/static/data/202221.webp'>",
    "correct_answer": "P: Application software, Q: Operating system, R: Hardware",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "P: Operating system, Q: Hardware, R: Application software",
      "P: Application software, Q: Hardware, R: Operating system",
      "P: Operating system, Q: Application software, R: Hardware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following describes the URL, <code>http://www.chris.edu.hk/ict</code>?",
    "correct_answer": "<code>ict</code> is a path on the web server",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The domain name is <code>chris</code>",
      "The web site is registered as a government organization in Hong Kong",
      "HTTPS is involved when navigating this URL"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of e-learning?",
    "correct_answer": "Students' need in computer resources is reduced",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Students' learning progress can be tracked",
      "Students' learning schedules can be more flexible",
      "Student can bring less physical books for learning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Fibre optics is used in a computer network because...",
    "correct_answer": "It supports a connection with a long distance",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It supports both wired and wireless connections",
      "It's cost is lower than other communication links",
      "It is very resistant to bending"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Internet Protocol (IP) is used in computer network because...",
    "correct_answer": "Data can be transmitted under the same communication rules",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Computers in the network are installed with the same operating system",
      "The maximum data transfer rates between computers are the same",
      "The network is a LAN instead of a WAN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Internet Services and Applications",
    "question": "Chris uses a computer to watch streaming videos. Which of the following should he consider?",
    "correct_answer": "Network bandwidth",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Anti-virus software",
      "Hard disk storage size",
      "CMOS battery life"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following considerations of an online banking application should be the least important?",
    "correct_answer": "Application file size",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Network security",
      "Personal data privacy",
      "Operating system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT appropriate when using a social media application?",
    "correct_answer": "Forward information sent from others to friends as soon as possible",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Read the terms and conditions before using the application",
      "Provide necessary personal information only",
      "Take a 5-minute rest from the device after using the application for 30 minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Chris installs the same software package on two computers. He does not infringe copyright because...",
    "correct_answer": "The license of the software package allows such installation",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The two computers are located in different countries",
      "The operating system of the two computers are different",
      "The trial period of the software package has not ended"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Technological Innovations",
    "question": "A humanoid robot is a robot resembling the human body in shape. Which of the following about the use of such robots is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "They will never make a mistake when performing a task",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "They can follow working procedures accurately",
      "They can take up dirty or dangerous jobs",
      "They can replace the work of some emplyees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Which of the following about direct access on a storage device is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "Writing of data in a file starts from the beginning of the storage device",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "In general, the seek time to search for a file is faster than that of sequential access",
      "It is also known as random access",
      "It is more commonly used in hard disks than sequential access"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Chris only has a single computer without any network connections. Which of the following processing is NOT possible for him to carry out?",
    "correct_answer": "Distributed processing",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Parallel processing",
      "Real-time processing",
      "Batch processing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "In which of the following addition of two 8-bit integers, it will result in an overflow error under sign-and-magnitude and two's complement representation?",
    "correct_answer": "0110 0000 + 0110 0000",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "1110 0000 + 1110 0000",
      "1000 0111 + 1000 0111",
      "1010 0101 + 0101 1010"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Complete the following SQL that displays each school with more than 5 students in the database and its corresponding number of student: <br> <code>SELECT School, COUNT(Name) FROM Table </code>...",
    "correct_answer": "<code>GROUP BY Country HAVING COUNT(Name) > 5</code>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<code>WHERE COUNT(Name) > 5 GROUP BY Country</code>",
      "<code>ORDER BY Country HAVING COUNT(Name) > 5</code>",
      "<code>WHERE COUNT(Name) > 5 ORDER BY Country</code>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "When entering formulae in a spreadsheet, which of the following results is NOT correct?",
    "correct_answer": "<code>MID('FuCKhK3Aa', 2, 3) = 'uC'</code>",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "<code>LEN('FuCKhK3Aa') = 9</code>",
      "<code>FIND('3A', 'FuCKhK3Aa') = 7</code>",
      "<code>LEFT('FuCKhK3Aa') = 'F'</code>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "Which of the following about Unicode and Big-5 code is true?",
    "correct_answer": "Unicode is used for representing characters in English and other language",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "In a computer, the use of Big-5 code and Unicode depends on the operating system",
      "Big-5 code is used for representing in Chinese only",
      "For web browsing, the use of a character set depends on the browser"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "For a CPU with the specifications of 16 cores, 5 GHz and a 30 MB cache, which of the following is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "The maximum number of programs that the CPU can handle at the same time is 16",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The clock rate of the CPU is 5 GHz",
      "The CPU accesses data in the cache memory faster than that in RAM",
      "The CPU accesses data in the registers faster than that in the cache memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Software",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a function of an operating system?",
    "correct_answer": "Store user programs permanently",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Allocate hardware recources",
      "Schedule jobs",
      "Manage network traffic and data flow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Input and Output Devices",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a specification of a projector?",
    "correct_answer": "5000 rpm (revolutions per minute)",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "8K UHD (Ultra High Definition) <img src='/static/data/8k.webp'>",
      "4K UHD (Ultra High Definition) <img src='/static/data/4k.webp'>",
      "3000 lm (lumen)",
      "WiFi 802.11ac supported"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "A web site uses third-party cookies to presonalize content and analyse web traffic. Which of the following is the consequence of accepting cookies?",
    "correct_answer": "Personal information may be collected",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The bandwidth of the network may be decreased",
      "The address book of his email account may be disclosed",
      "The chance of getting phishing emails may increased"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris uploads a photo to his social media account through a browser. Which of the following protocols may be involved?",
    "correct_answer": "All of the options",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "IP",
      "DNS",
      "HTTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "In the following diagram, a computer is connected to the Internet. What is X? <br> <img src='/static/data/202323.webp'>",
    "correct_answer": "Modem",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Switch",
      "Router",
      "Access Point (AP)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following about IP addresses is NOT true?",
    "correct_answer": "They are used to reassemble the data received back into the original order",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "They contain location information and make network devices accessible for communication",
      "They can be used with both the Internet and Intranet",
      "They uniquely identify a device on the Internet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following is the common input and output of a domain name system (DNS) server?",
    "correct_answer": "Domain name -> IP address",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Domain name -> MAC address",
      "MAC address -> Domain name",
      "HTML -> Domain name"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Which of the following is advantage of using open source software over freeware?",
    "correct_answer": "Users can improve the source code and share it in the community",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "It is easier to set up and use",
      "Open source software is cross-platform",
      "Freeware cannot be used without paying for it"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following programs can enhance the security of using a computer?",
    "correct_answer": "An encryption program",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Adware",
      "Ransomware",
      "An Trojan program"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is advantage of using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) on web sites?",
    "correct_answer": "The transferred data is encrypted",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data transfer rate is higher",
      "Power consumption of data transmission can be reduced",
      "The IP addresses of the web sites can be hidden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Intellectual Property",
    "question": "Why do many companies prefer commercial software to open source software?",
    "correct_answer": "Commercial software developers can provide better support",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Open source software contains more software bugs",
      "Open source software cannot be modified by companies",
      "Open source software cannot be used freely after trial period"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "How can updaing an operating system frequently protect computers from virus attack?",
    "correct_answer": "Security loopholes can be fixed",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "More support from the developer of the operating system can be provided",
      "The company performance can be enhanced",
      "A virus check can be conducted"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "What is the range of 64-bit two's complement?",
    "correct_answer": "-2^63 to 2^63 - 1",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "-2^63 to 2^63",
      "-2^63 + 1 to 2^63 - 1",
      "-2^63 + 1 to 2^63"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Multimedia Elements and Digitization",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT image file format?",
    "correct_answer": "MPEG4",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "PNG",
      "AI",
      "TIFF"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Number and Character Encoding System",
    "question": "A text file contains English, Traditional Chinese and Simplified Chinese characters. Which character set should be used?",
    "correct_answer": "UTF-8",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "ASCII",
      "Big-5 code",
      "GB code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "A MAC address composed of 6 groups of 2 hexadecimal digits, as shown in the following example: <br> <code>1A:2B:3C:4D:5E:6F</code> <br> How many possible addresses can this format represent?",
    "correct_answer": "2^48",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "2^24",
      "2^12",
      "2^64"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
    "correct_answer": "Queries in the database are used to extract information from it",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Reports in the database are used to help users store data",
      "Forms in the database are used to summarize the information from it in a structured way",
      "Filering and sorting of data can be saved for future use"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "What is the advantage of entering data into a database using forms?",
    "correct_answer": "Convenient data entry",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Faster data filtering",
      "Smaller data storage size",
      "Faster execution of SQL"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Spreadsheet",
    "question": "<img src='/static/data/202411.webp'> <br> What is the results of the following formula? <br> <code>=RANK(B1,B1:B5,0) + RANK(B2,B1:B5,1)</code>",
    "correct_answer": "7",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "4",
      "8",
      "6"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Database",
    "question": "Which of the following membership data of a sports association can be defined as a boolean data type?",
    "correct_answer": "VIP member",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Bank account number",
      "Education level",
      "Member ID"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Chris experienced a power failure while working on a desktop computer. Some of the data in progress could be recovered. Why?",
    "correct_answer": "The data in progress is stored on the hard drive",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The data in progress is stored in RAM",
      "The data in progress is stored in ROM",
      "The data in progress is stored in CPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Chris found that his computer was infected with ransomware. What should he do immediately?",
    "correct_answer": "Disconnect from the network and shut down the computer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Run antivirus software to scan and remove the virus",
      "Install a firewall to block unauthorized access",
      "Format the hard drive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Computer Hardware",
    "question": "Where is the boot program used to start the computer usually stored?",
    "correct_answer": "ROM",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "RAM",
      "CPU",
      "SSD"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "The Networking and Internet Basics",
    "question": "Chris registered the domain name <code>chris.edu.hk</code>. Which of the following URLs can he use?",
    "correct_answer": "zh.chris.edu.hk",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "hk.chris.edu",
      "chris.com.hk",
      "chris.hk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Data Organization and Data Control",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the task displayed on the login screen of an online store? <br> <img src='/static/data/202435.webp'>",
    "correct_answer": "To confirm that the login is performed by a human",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "To ensure that the login device is equipped with a touchscreen",
      "To verify that the login information is correct",
      "To ensure that the user's computer has enough computational power"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "When Chris registered as a user on a website, he received an SMS message from the site with a code to enter. What is the purpose of this code?",
    "correct_answer": "To verify his identity",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "To ensure the SMS message is not spam",
      "To ensure the website and his account are protected by SSL",
      "To check whether his phone can receive SMS message"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Health and Ethical Issues",
    "question": "What ergonomic improvements need to be made when using the following computer?",
    "correct_answer": "Install armrests on the chair",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Install a trackball",
      "Install a touchscreen",
      "Use a smaller table"
    ]
  },
  {
    "topic": "Threats and Security on the Internet",
    "question": "Which of the following is the main function of PKI?",
    "correct_answer": "Ensuring the integrity of data transmitted over the Internet",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Encrypting data to prevent unauthorized access",
      "Storing large amounts of data securely",
      "Providing high-speed internet connectivity"
    ]
  }
]